これら４つの要素を 四大行と呼び 「発」…　「練」で増大させた 念オーラを最終的に発する技 念能力を使いこなすための 基礎になるのだ あらゆる強さを得るのに 不可欠な要素だ これにより　肉体は強靭となり 若さも保つ 「纏」　念オーラを 体の周囲に　とどめる技 「絶」　念オーラを完全に絶つ技 「練」　念オーラのエネルギーを 増大させる技 自身の気配を消したり 疲労回復に効果がある
Would you allow us to have names?
どうしても　今 戦ってみたいんだ！
NGL, huh? They believe living naturally is always better.
２００階クラスの初戦
They may be weird for living there, but you guys are weird for coming to visit, too.
ゴンは　敵の思いもよらぬ攻撃に さらされていた
No idea what's going on, but I've already driven in about
ten similar groups today alone.
ヘッヘッヘッ…。
Then it sounds like we're
among the last to arrive.
うわ！
Somehow, they've managed
to obtain this information.
またしても 背後から独楽が直撃！
But are there really bugs
四方八方から攻めて来る 舞闘独楽に ゴン選手　初めての大ピンチ！
large enough to attack humans?
くっ…。 うわ！
It defies common sense, but that voice they heard over the transmitter... M-Monsters...
クリーンヒット＆ダウン！ ポイント２！
Giant bugs!
ギド選手 早くも４ポイント獲得！ やれるか？ もちろん！
It could be some other kind of organism.
独楽の数が多過ぎて 動きを見切れない　クッソ！ どうする？
NGL is one big nature reserve, so it's said to be inhabited by many organisms
that haven't been reported in academic circles.
師範代　あれも 「念」を使ってるんですか？
It wouldn't be strange if there are
insects that attack humans.
ええ　あれは「発」の一種。 物質にオーラを 送り込んでいるのです。 そうすると　その物質が 本来持つ　働きや動きを
Even if there aren't any giant bugs, this trip will be worth it if we can confirm the
existence of any unidentified organisms.
より強力に　できるのです。 小さなものなら少量のオーラで
As a new Magical Beast Hunter,
I need to produce results.
大きなものなら 大量のオーラを必要とします。
Now that I'm here, I have
to accomplish something.
彼が独楽に対して 強い思い入れを持っているから。 波長の合う者に対して ものは　より強い働きで 応えてくれるのです。
According to the scouts that
went out first thing this morning, a new human village has been discovered in sector MA18, in the southwest.
目で追おうとしても　ダメだ！ 独楽には「念」が込められている その気配を感じ取るんだ
There are twelve houses, with anywhere from twenty to sixty residents. Hey, that's pretty big.
うん　分かるぞ…
Guess there are still a few large villages left.
あっ！ 「纏」が消えかかってる！
I thought we'd already cleaned out that area.
うわ！ またも直撃！ ゴン選手　なすすべなし！
Then I will add this village to our
list of targets for the day.
場外へ　はじき出された！
Colt, could you make the trip?
うっ！
Roger. What's this, Peggy?
これでポイントは　６対０！ さぁ　後がなくなって来たぞ！
You aren't sending me? Cheetu, I need you to go northwest,
as originally planned.
ダメだ！ 気配を読むのに集中すると
Zazan, you accompany him.
自分の「纏」が　おろそかになって 解けてしまう どうすれば…
There aren't any large villages
left in the northwest.
ん？
Even if there were, there probably
aren't any strong, young humans.
はじかれた独楽が外に？ でも　俺を 襲って来るわけじゃ　ない…
It's more fun when I get to chase them around. Cheetu!
どうした？　試合続行するかね？
We do not hunt for amusement.
ちょっと黙ってて！ 今　考えてるから！
We serve the Queen.
カウント１０以内に戻らなければ 負けとするよ！ ワン！
We need only capture the
requested number of humans.
そういえば 独楽の「念」そのものには
I know that, Colt. We'll get the job done.
それほど嫌な感じはしない
Right, Zazan?
他の独楽は てんでバラバラに動いてる
I'll fulfill the quota.
所々で　ぶつかり合って…
But I don't need you telling
me how to hunt my prey.
もしかしたら　独楽は俺だけ 襲って来るわけじゃないのかな
I'll do things my own way.
フォー！ おじさんは何で場外にいるの？
It's fun to hunt humans when
they're running around. What did you say?
リングにいたら 私まで攻撃されるからだ！
Well, there you go.
ファイブ！ やっぱり！
Let's go, Zazan.
ただの独楽に高度な命令を 与えるのは不可能です。
You'll have an easier time if you learn to relax.
恐らく　ギドが独楽に念じたのは
They dare do things their own way?
「邪魔者を　はじき飛ばせ」。
At this rate, their squadrons will fall apart!
ただ　グルグルと土俵を回り続け
While the use of names
偶然ぶつかったものを はじき飛ばすだけ。 セブン！
is convenient for leading the troops, we don't want to encourage too much individuality.
だったら　独楽自体を そんなに怖がることは　ない
Their behavior could lead to
a breakdown in command.
独楽は　ほっといて 奴を攻撃だ！
We must take steps.
えい！
I agree that something must be done.
フン！　たとえ　分かったところで 俺への攻撃は無駄だね！ あっ！
Meleoron and Yunju have yet to
show themselves at a war council.
出た！　ギド選手の 攻防一体　必殺奥義
Meleoron! Stop hiding, and show yourself!
うわ！ ゴン選手に強裂なカウンター！
Just to be clear, it isn't my fault Yunju is absent.
スリーポイント！ ジャッジは　クリティカルとダウンを宣言！
You were hiding because you
thought you'd be blamed?
これで　合計９ポイント！ ホントにホントの崖っぷち！
You're supposed to be a squadron leader. Where is Yunju? Why is he not here?
ヘッヘッヘッ。
See? I'm the one getting yelled at.
自ら独楽と化し　身を守りながら 攻撃は　舞闘独楽に任せる。
That's why I didn't want to come out. It's always my fault.
地味だが　確実にポイントを稼げる 戦い方ってやつさ。
You're just as guilty for hiding the truth. And further... I'll talk!
ギドを倒す方法は いくつかあります。
It isn't like I wanted to cover for him or anything.
彼が疲れ果て　「纏」を解くまで 攻撃を続けるとか
He's the one who ran off on
his own to hunt humans.
彼の防御力以上の「発」で 吹き飛ばすとか。
What? Toward which sector?
どの方法にしても　大量のオーラを 生み出さねばならない。
Was a new village discovered? That's not it!
しかし　ゴンくんは「練」…
You remember the humans who fought back?
オーラを瞬時に生み出す すべを知らない。
The ones who were armed with guns. Yunju was
どれだけ早く 大量のオーラを生み出し それを攻撃力に変えて 相手に　ぶつけるか
all worked up about making them his pets.
どうすれば もっと戦っていられる？
Come on! What are you doing?
あと１ポイント取られたら　終わり でも　まだ戦っていたい！
I accidentally stepped on you. You're supposed to entertain us more! That's right!
今の俺に　できること それは…
Run for your lives!
ゴン！ あっ！
Until you're dead.
「纏」を解いた!? 何て　むちゃなことを！ ただ解いただけじゃ　ない
Those two huge trees serve as
the checkpoint and embassy.
あれは…　「絶」
What's out here, in the middle of nowhere?
自らの気配を完全に絶つ技 もちろん　精孔も閉じられて オーラは消える！
These people are all so weird.
「念」に対する防御は 完全にゼロ！
Stay alert.
「絶」は教えていない… 私に会う前から独学で？ だとしたら　「絶」と知ってて 覚えたんじゃ　ない
The Ants are a concern, but the NGL is
more than a nature-loving organization. Got it.
恐らく　生活の中で 獣が獲物を捕まえるために
What brings you here?
自然と覚えるように…
We're on a hunt.
すごい資質を 持っているはずだ！
A quarantined organism may
have invaded this country.
バッカ野郎！　「念」の攻撃を 無防備で受けちまったら 生身の体は ひとたまりも　ないんだぞ！
If you are pro Hunters, then we cannot deny you entry.
分かってる！ でも　複雑な独楽の動きを
Follow me.
あの子は　命懸けで…
You're using computers and machines.
命懸けで　修行をしているのか！ ハッハッハッ！ 命がいらぬか　小僧！
This place isn't within NGL's borders.
ならば　望み通り　死ぬんだな！
This area is used for foreign relations
and information exchange. Are there any facilities similar
to this within the country?
何!?
No machines of any kind are allowed inside NGL.
ゴン選手が攻撃回避！
Naturally, visitors are also not allowed
感じる… 動きが　分かる！ 今の俺に　できること…
to bring any inside. Which means that you'll need
to remove all metallic, petroleum, glass, or other
such goods on your person.
全力で 敵の攻撃をよけること！
D-Does that include my glasses? Yes.
これで　まだ…　戦える！
You're telling us to strip naked? Don't worry.
亀裂骨折が１２か所 全治４か月だとさ。
Only the five of us are left?
この　どアホ！ ごめん　エヘっ。
I want you to stand by in the closest town. We'll return here within two
weeks and contact you. Got it.
俺に謝っても仕方ねえだろ！ 一体どうなってんだ　この中はよ！
The checkpoint is over there.
嫌ってほど見てたろうが！ 一歩間違えば お前も　ああなってたんだ！ この程度で済んだこと自体 ラッキーなんだぞ。 ったく　何のために眼鏡にいさんが 教えてくれたと思ってんだか。
There will be a physical exam and interview, as well as metal, x-ray, and ultrasound scanning.
う…　でもさ 大丈夫かなって思ったんだよね。
The security is rather strict.
何回か攻撃を受けてみて　まぁ 急所さえ外せば死ぬことは…。
Some people have smuggled in guns by
hiding the parts inside their bodies.
あ…　うぅ…。 うっ　あっ…！
It's common for people to hide cameras
or cell phones in their rectums.
眼鏡にいさん！　あ…。
All of you are clean.
あっ…。
Thank you for your patience.
あの…　ごめんなさ…。
Please pass through.
あっ　それ　俺が言っといた。 はぁ…。
Okay, let's begin the hunt.
キルアくん　ゴンくんの完治は いつ頃になるか知ってますか？
Any sightings of giant insects?
医者は　２か月くらいって 言ってたけど。
I haven't heard anything.
分かりました。 サンキュー　キルア
Even if there were any such creatures, the citizens in this country wouldn't
make much of a fuss.
では　今日から２か月間 一切の試合を禁じます。 「念」の修行　および「念」について 調べることも許しません。
If we are attacked and killed by animals, that is simply nature taking its course.
どうですか？ 分かった　ちゃんと守るよ。
Anyway, we should follow the
coast and check the villages.
左手を。 誓いの糸です。
If we go through all of them
and nothing turns up, it probably isn't in this country.
これを見て 常に約束を忘れぬように。
That's assuming those guys
were telling the truth.
うん。 キルアくん　ちょっと…。 ん？
They're still following us, aren't they? Yeah...
キルアくん　君達の 本当の目的は何なのですか？
in case we encounter unknown tribes and
require interpreters or intermediaries. But they're obviously here to watch us.
いや　目的って言われてもなぁ。 ズシと　あんたに会わなきゃ
Well, I never expected the people
here to be of any help.
俺は　小遣い稼ぎだけの つもりだったし
My gut
ゴンは　ヒソカって奴と戦うために 武者修行に来てるんだ。 それだけだよ。
tells me that it's here.
あぁ　ゴンは… うん…　分からないけど。
Don't move.
あいつ　口では「ヒソカと戦えれば それでいい」とか言ってるけど
If you die, it won't be my fault.
昨日の試合のやり方　あれは
A-A mere animal shouldn't order
a superior human around!
スリルを 楽しんでるみたいだったからな。
Mere animal? Superior human?
)
I don't understand... How are you and I different?
((この攻防は　一体 いつまで続くのでしょうか！))
Shut up!
すでに５０近くに なっているはず！))
Good grief...
((ゴン選手　その複雑無限の独楽嵐を ことごとく　よけています！))
Didn't your parents ever teach you to answer a question when you're asked?
((独楽を出し尽くしたギド選手も 観客と共に　ただ見入るだけ！))
There's no hope for you, old-timer.
)
Try harder in your next life.
楽しんでいた…　と？ ああ　俺も　そういうところ ないわけじゃないから
If you kill him, we aren't able to store him.
分かるんだけどさ。 俺なら 時と場合と相手を選ぶけど
I can make meatballs to serve
to the Queen within the day.
あいつは夢中になったら 見境なさそうだしな。
People like him irritate me.
あっ　でも　同じ約束を２度 破るような奴じゃないから大丈夫。
They don't know their place.
もしかして　私は… もう遅いよ。
I prefer to see them running around in fear.
もう　知っちゃったんだから 俺もゴンも。
Yesterday, you shot one in
the back when they ran.
教えたこと　後悔してやめるなら
If you'd let me handle this, I could secure
our prey in a smarter fashion.
他の誰かに教わるか 自分で覚えるかするだけ。
When you said, "Don't move,"
that was meant for me, right?
責任　感じることないよ。 俺の兄貴も　ヒソカも 「念」の使い手だったんだから
Giving your squadron leader an order, huh?
いずれ　俺もゴンも 「念」にたどり着いていた。
Don't get too cocky.
分かりました 途中で降りる気はありませんよ。
I'm forgiving, so I'll let it slide.
むしろ伝えたいことが 山ほどありますから。 ズシが宿で待っています。
If you enjoy killing so much, you should
volunteer for the feeding squad.
いや…　いいや。 えっ？
No hope...
ゴンくんに伝えてください！ 燃えるほうの「燃」の修行なら 認めると。
Damn that Yunju.
「点」を毎日　行うようにと！
Shut up!
もしかしたら　私は…
Huh? I don't see any problem.
とんでもない怪物を
I enjoy what I do.
起こしてしまったのかも しれません
You want to take this one?
うっ…。
Oh, Zazan... That nasty woman.
師範代？
You have my sympathy.
どういうことだ！
I hear that they're allowed to
kill any humans they want.
自力で　この斡旋所 見つけたくらいだから 頭が切れることは認めるよ。
If you take this as a gift, they'll probably let you join on the spot.
経験不足とか 言うつもりはないわ。
What is this?
ひよっこでもいいっていう客は いるし。
It's terrible... Who did this?
でも…　あなた ひよっこ以前なんだよねぇ。
A gun?
どういう意味だ!? ちゃんと　ハンターライセンスは 持っていると言ってるだろ。
People are fighting with guns! Who could it be?
だけど　あんたの試験は まだ終わっちゃいない。
Guns aren't allowed in NGL!
見れば分かる。 何だと？
They're members of the NGL
underground that manufactures D². Huh?
何が見える？ は？ 私の横にさ。
I don't think these wounds
were inflicted by humans. Does that mean...
何も見えないでしょ？ 見えるようになったら もういっぺん　おいでよ。
But if the monster we seek
was responsible for this, we won't be able to handle it
with our current members.
一体　何が… 何が見えないというのだ
Monsters! Ponzu! Balda! Pekuba! Run on my signal.
あっ…！
No hope.
こいつを　すり取ったどころか
Are you okay?
街で俺と　すれ違ったことすら 気づかなかったろ。 貴様！ 私のハンターライセンスを返せ！
Yes... Anyway, we should contact
the other pro Hunters. Can you handle that, Ponzu?
「念」も知らない見習いに
Got it.
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
What? That's it?
分かったか？ お前には　まだ足りねえんだよ。
No, there are more.
私は… 私には… １人で戦い抜ける力が　いる！
There sure are! I can smell living humans!
本当の試験は　これからだ。
What do we do, Zaikahal?
隠された才能を 覚醒させつつあるゴン
As the Chimera Ants continue their rampage, they have cornered the country's shadowy ruler.
そして　今またクラピカも
A storm brews in NGL.
新しい力に出あい 歩き出そうとしていた
And Gon's group is heading straight for it.